It all ends.
Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows: Part 2 is a
adventure, fantasy film directed by David Yates.
Harry, Ron and Hermione continue their quest to
vanquish the evil Voldemort once and for all.
Just as things begin to look hopeless for the young wizards, Harry discovers a trio of
magical objects that endow him with powers to rival Voldemort's formidable skills.
Harry Potter, played by Daniel Radcliffe.
Hermione Granger, played by Emma Watson.
Ron Weasley, played by Rupert Grint.
Lord Voldemort, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Severus Snape, played by Alan Rickman.
Albus Dumbledore, played by Michael Gambon.
Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 2 is a 2011 fantasy film
directed by David Yates from a screenplay by Steve Kloves.
It is the second of two cinematic parts based on the 2007 novel by J.
Rowling, and the eighth and final instalment of the Harry Potter film series.
The story concludes Harry Potter's final quest to find and destroy Lord
Voldemort's Horcruxes in order to destroy him once and for all.
The film stars an ensemble cast comprising Daniel Radcliffe as Harry Potter, and Rupert Grint and Emma Watson as Harry's best friends, Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger, alongside Helena
Bonham Carter, Robbie Coltrane, Warwick Davis, Ralph Fiennes, Michael Gambon, John Hurt, Jason Isaacs, Gary Oldman, Alan Rickman, Maggie Smith, David Thewlis, and Julie Walters.
Principal photography began on 19 February 2009, and was completed on 12
June 2010, with reshoots taking place in December 2010.
Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 2 was released by Warner Bros.
Pictures in the United Kingdom and United States on 15 July 2011, and
is the only Harry Potter film to be released in 3D.
The film was praised as a satisfying conclusion to the saga, and for the visual effects,
performances, action sequences, direction, musical score, and cinematography.
It grossed over $1.3 billion worldwide, becoming the third-highest-grossing film
during its run, and the highest-grossing film in the Harry Potter series.
The National Board of Review named Deathly Hallows –
Part 2 one of the top-ten films of 2011.
It was nominated for three awards at the 84th Academy
Awards, and received numerous other accolades.
The film explores themes of witch, dying and death,
saving the world, self sacrifice, magic.